musingssahm.com 2019-12-21

# Privacy Policy - Living Well Mom

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully before using this Website.

#### **Privacy Policy Consent**

The Website and its Content is owned by Erika Bragdon, Owner, of Living Well Mom, LLC. (“Company”, “we”, or “us”). The term “you” refers to the user or viewer of our Website.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy on the Website at any time without notice. Use of any information or contribution that you provide to us, or which is collected by us on or through our Website or its Content is governed by this Privacy Policy. By using our Website or its Content, you consent to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, please do not use our Website or its Content.

#### **Information We May Collect**

To use our Website or its Content, we may seek personal data including your name, e-mail address, street address, city, state, billing information, or other personally identifying information (“Confidential Information”), or you may offer or provide a comment, photo, image, video or any other submission to us when visiting or interacting with our Website and its Content (“Other Information”). By providing such Confidential Information or Other Information to us, you grant us permission to use and store such information.

We collect personal information from you so that we can provide you with a positive experience when utilizing our Website or content. We will only collect the minimum amount of information necessary for us to fulfill our obligation to you.We may collect:

  * A name and an email address so we can deliver content that you have requested, such as our newsletter, webinar information, etc – you would be consenting to this by providing this information to us in our contact forms.
  * Billing information including name, address and credit card information so that we can process payment to deliver our products or services to you under our contractual obligation.
  * A name and an email address if you complete our contact form with a question. We may send you marketing emails with either your consent or if we believe we have a legitimate interest to contact you based on your contact or question.
  * Information from you from a co-branded offer. In this case, we will make clear as to who is collecting the information and whose privacy policy applies. If both / all parties are retaining the information you provide, this will also be made clear, as will links to all privacy policies.
  * Demographic information. There may be an occasion where we may ask for demographic information such as gender or age, but if you choose not to provide such data and information, you may still use the Website and its Content, but you may not be able to use those services where demographic information may be required.

Please note that the information above (“Personal Data”) that you are giving to us is voluntarily, and by providing this information to us you are giving consent for us to use, collect and process this Personal Data. You are welcome to opt-out or request for us to delete your Personal Data at any point by contacting us at erika(at)livingwellmom.com.

If you choose not to provide us with certain Personal Data, you may not be able to participate in certain aspects of our Website or Content.

#### **Other Information We May Collect**

  1. **Anonymous Data Collection and Use**  
To maintain our Website’s high quality, we may use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer the Website by identifying which areas of the Website are most heavily used, and to display content according to your preferences. Your IP address is the number assigned to computers connected to the Internet. This is essentially “traffic data” which is not used to personally identify you but is helpful to us for marketing purposes and for improving our services. We may also track your use of the site, including pages visited and the time spent on each page. The purpose of collecting this information is to provide you with the best possible service, to ensure the accuracy and efficiency of our search engine, and to measure the use of this website and to improve its content and performance. To the extent we share such information with third parties, it is not traceable to any particular user and will not be used to contact you, but may be used to tailor ads. Anonymous traffic data may also be shared with business partners and advertisers on an aggregate basis.
  2. **Use of “Cookies”**  
We may use the standard “cookies” feature of major web browsers. We do not set any personally identifiable information in cookies, nor do we employ any data capture mechanisms on our Website other than cookies. You may choose to disable cookies through your own web browser’s settings. However, disabling this function may diminish your experience on the Website and some features may not work as intended. We have no access to or control over any information collected by other individuals, companies or entities whose website or materials may be linked to our Website or its Content. Most browsers support cookies, but users can set their browsers to decline them and can delete them whenever they like. A third-party website called aboutcookies.org has been set up to help you with instructions how you can do that on various browsers.

#### **What We Do with Information We Collect**

  1. **Contact You**  
We may contact you with information that you provide to us based on the following:  
a) Consent. We may contact you if you give us your clear consent to contact you.  
b) Contract. We will contact you under our contractual obligation to deliver goods or services you purchase from us.  
c) Reasonable Interest. We may contact you if we feel you have a reasonable interest in hearing from us. For example, if you sign up for a weekly newsletter, we may send you marketing emails on our self-care course for moms. You will always have the option to opt out of any of our emails.
  2. **Process Payments**  
We will use the Personal Data you give to us in order to process your payment for the purchase of goods or services under a contract. We only use third party payment processors that take the utmost care in securing data.
  3. **Targeted Social Media Advertisements**  
We may use the data you provide to us to run social media advertisements and/or create look-alike audiences for advertisements.
  4. **Share with Third Parties**  
We may share your information with trusted third parties such as our newsletter provider in order to contact you via email, or our merchant accounts to process payments, and Google / social media accounts in order to run advertisements and our affiliates.

#### **Viewing by Others**

Note that whenever you voluntarily make your Confidential Information or Other Information available for viewing by others online through this Website or its Content, it may be seen, collected and used by others, and therefore, we cannot be responsible for any unauthorized or improper use of the Confidential Information or Other Information that you voluntarily share.

#### **Submission, Storage, Sharing and Transferring of Personal Data**

Personal Data that you provide to us is stored internally or through a data management system. Your Personal Data will only be accessed by those who help to obtain, manage or store that information, or who have a legitimate need to know such Personal Data (i.e., our hosting provider, newsletter provider, payment processors or team members).

It is important to note that we may transfer data internationally. By using our Website and providing us with your Personal Data, you consent to these transfers in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

#### **Data Retention**

We retain your Personal Data for the minimum amount of time necessary to provide you with the information and/or services that you requested from us. We may include certain Personal Data for longer periods of time if necessary for legal, contractual and accounting obligations.

#### **Confidentiality**

We aim to keep the Confidential Information that you share with us confidential. Please note that we may disclose such Confidential Information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that: (1) such action is necessary to protect and defend our rights or property or those of our users or licensees, (2) to act as immediately necessary in order to protect the personal safety or rights of our users or the public, or (3) to investigate or respond to any real or perceived violation of this Privacy Policy or of our Disclaimer, Terms and Conditions, or any other terms of use or agreement with us.

#### **Passwords**

To use certain features of the Website or its Content, you may need a username and password. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of the username and password, and you are responsible for all activities, whether by you or by others, that occur under your username or password and within your account. You agree to notify us immediately of any unauthorized or improper use of your username or password or any other breach of security. To help protect against unauthorized or improper use, make sure that you log out at the end of each session requiring your username and password.

It is your responsibility to protect your own username and password from disclosure to others. We cannot and will not be liable for any loss or damage arising from your failure to protect your username, password or account information. If you share your username or password with others, they may be able to obtain access to your personal information at your own risk.

By using our Website and its Content you agree to enter true and accurate information on the Website and its Content. If you enter a bogus email address we have the right to immediately deactivate and remove your account.

We will use our best efforts to keep your username and password(s) private and will not otherwise share your password(s) without your consent, except as necessary when the law requires it or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary, particularly when disclosure is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to others or interfering with our rights or property.

#### **Unsubscribe**

You may unsubscribe to our e-newsletters or updates at any time through the unsubscribe link at the footer of all e-mail communications.

We manage email lists through a list management system. Unsubscribing from one list managed by us will not necessarily remove you from all publication email lists. If you have questions or are experiencing problems unsubscribing, please contact us at erika(at)livingwellmom.com.

#### **Security**

We only share your Personal Data with trusted third parties who use the same level of care in processing your Personal Data as we do. That being said, we cannot guarantee that your Personal Data will always be secure due to technology or security breaches. Should there be a data breach of which we are aware, we will inform you immediately.

#### **Anti-Spam Policy**

We have a no spam policy and provide you with the ability to opt-out of our communications by selecting the unsubscribe link at the footer of all e-mails. We have taken the necessary steps to ensure that we are compliant with the CAN-SPAM Act of 2003 by never sending out misleading information. We will not sell, rent or share your email address.

#### **Third Party Websites**

We may link to other websites on our Website. We have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of any other individual, company or entity whose website or materials may be linked to our Website or its content, and thus we cannot be held liable for the privacy of the information on their website or that you voluntarily share with their website. Please review their privacy policies for guidelines as to how they respectively store, use and protect the privacy of your Personal Data.

#### **Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance**

We do not knowingly collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age in compliance with COPPA (Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act), and our Website and its Content is directed to individuals who are at least 13 years old or older.

#### **Anonymous Data Collection and Use**

To maintain our Website’s high quality, we may use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer the Website by identifying which areas of the Website are most heavily used, and to display content according to your preferences. Your IP address is the number assigned to computers connected to the Internet. This is essentially “traffic data” which cannot personally identify you, but is helpful to us for marketing purposes and for improving our services. Traffic data collection does not follow a user’s activities on any other Websites in any way. Anonymous traffic data may also be shared with business partners and advertisers on an aggregate basis.

#### **Privacy Policies of Other Websites**

We have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of any other individual, company or entity whose website or materials may be linked to our Website or its Content, and thus we cannot be held liable for the privacy of the information on their website or that you voluntarily share with their website. Please review their privacy policies for guidelines as to how they respectively store, use and protect the privacy of your Confidential Information and Other Information.

#### **Assignment of Rights**

In the event of an assignment, sale, joint venture, or other transfer of some or all of our assets, you agree we can assign, sell, license or transfer any information that you have provided to us. Please note, however, that any purchasing party is prohibited from using the Confidential Information or Other Information submitted to us under this Privacy Policy in a manner that is materially inconsistent with this Privacy Policy without your prior consent.

#### **Notification of Changes**

We may use your contact information to inform you of changes to the Website or its Content, or, if requested, to send you additional information about us. We reserve the right, at our sole discretion, to change, modify or otherwise alter our Website, its Content and this Privacy Policy at any time. Such changes and/or modifications shall become effective immediately upon posting our updated Privacy Policy. Please review this Privacy Policy periodically. Continued use of any of information obtained through or on the Website or its Content following the posting of changes and/or modifications constitutes acceptance of the revised Privacy Policy.

### Advertising Privacy Statement

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site. AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behavior on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed. Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third-party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: https://adssettings.google.com. You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: http://optout.networkadvertising.org. However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

**For European Economic Area Residents**

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing. If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact us at erika(at)livingwellmom.com and contact AdThrive at info@adthrive.com. If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences link at the bottom of the site. (Available in the EU.)

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at erika(at)livingwellmom.com
